Coordonnées

www.linkedin.com/in/maxime-laasri-41306674 (LinkedIn)

Principales compétences

Electrical Engineering
Energy Industry
Project Management

Languages

Anglais (Full Professional)
Espagnol (Professional Working)
Français (Native or Bilingual)

Certifications

Neural Networks and Deep Learning

Publications

An Overview of Uncertainty Quantification Methods for Infinite Neural Networks

Maxime Laasri

Software Engineer in Machine Learning at Roku, Inc. États-Unis

Résumé

Graduate student in Data Science at Harvard University. Crossregistered at MIT.

Formerly a research project manager with 7 years of experience in applied mathematical optimization for the energy industry, focusing on long-term modeling for cross-border electricity trading. Led, planned, and executed research projects involving multi-million-euro budgets. Designed and developed scientific models as well as industrial tools for future power systems. Managed international teams, with responsibility for the budget, schedule, and quality of deliverables ranging from energy models to European energy policy recommendations for the European Commission.

Expérience

Roku Inc.

Software Engineer in Machine Learning, Voice Edge ML Team janvier 2023 - Present (4 mois)

Boston, Massachusetts, United States

Building and quantizing machine learning models for performing speech recognition and voice processing on Roku devices

Harvard University

Master's student in data science
août 2021 - mars 2023 (1 an 8 mois)

Boston Area, Massachusetts, United States

Pursuing a Master's degree in data science at Harvard University, John A. Paulson School Of Engineering And Applied Sciences.

Sample courses: Machine Learning (Harvard), Advanced Scientific Computing: Stochastic Methods for Data Analysis, Inference and Optimization (Harvard), Computer Vision (MIT), Computer Graphics (MIT)

Roku Inc.

Software Engineer Intern in Machine Learning for Audio juin 2022 - août 2022 (3 mois)

Boston, Massachusetts, United States

Prototyped new voice processing features for Roku devices using state-of-theart research in deep learning for audio

Réseau de Transport d'Électricité 7 ans

Research project manager, R&D Department juin 2018 - août 2021 (3 ans 3 mois)

La Défense

Led a Europe-wide team of 20 industry researchers and academics to deliver simulation-supported recommendations on energy policy to the European Commission

Provided market design recommendations to the worldwide consortium for power system expertise CIGRE, as French delegate to its short-term energy markets taskforce

Developed and managed a cloud platform dedicated to data-intensive research studies on conventional and green energy trading, overseeing a €2M budget

Worked on an energy-reserve co-optimization model for the European market, using mixed-integer linear programming and duality theory

Taught a two-month long course on the use of mathematical optimization in R&D for the energy industry as a lecturer at École des Mines de Paris

Research engineer, R&D Department juin 2016 - juin 2018 (2 ans 1 mois)
La Défense

Led the industrialization of a Matlab-based algorithm I designed using dynamic programming and Bellman optimality theory to incentivize French suppliers towards long-term investments in the power industry

Conceived the market clearing algorithm of a European platform which facilitates 15-minute energy trading between grid operators and service providers

Developed RTE's pricing strategy for European balancing platforms, based on new EU regulations giving priority to EU-based platforms over national balancing mechanisms

Implemented a new agent-based model in Python for simulating electricity markets using mixed-integer linear programming, Bellman optimality theory, and reinforcement learning

Organized multiple events and conferences on grid balancing for the R&D Department and the whole company

Research engineer, Market Department septembre 2014 - juin 2016 (1 an 10 mois)
La Défense

Designed a simulation model of the European grid for the French Government, to assess the profitability of trending smart-grid technologies. The model includes Monte-Carlo simulations, risk management modeling, and LP

Designed, implemented, and deployed an algorithm for all operations teams across France, to predict power generation companies' opportunity cost when restrained by RTE's grid maintenance

Thales
Data Center Intern
juin 2013 - juillet 2013 (2 mois)
Yvelines, France

Server inventory and computer rack installation followed by its electrical setup and IT configurations.

Formation

Harvard University

Master of Science - MS, Data science · (août 2021 - décembre 2022)

IFP School

Master of Science - MS, Energy and Markets · (2014 - 2016)

CentraleSupelec

Master of Science - MS, Engineering · (2014 - 2016)

CentraleSupelec

Bachelor of Science - BS, Engineering · (2012 - 2014)

Lycée Hoche

Undergraduate preparatory program for nationwide competitive exams in science, Majored in Mathematics, Physics, and Computer science · (septembre 2010 - juin 2012)